What are you looking at?
你們在看什麼？
A poster for that WWI movie I'm in. Check it out.
我演的一次大戰電影海報 你看
Wow! It looks really violent!
看起來真的好暴力
I know. I'm coming soon to a theater near you.
我知道 我即將在各大戲院露面
I'm in THX. I'm unsuitable for children!
我用的是THX系統 我不適合孩子們觀看
-I cannot wait to see this. -It's generating Oscar buzz.
-我等不及要看這個 -它有拿下奧斯卡金像獎的希望
-I started that! -I thought I did!
-是我開始的 -我以為是我
I just talked to my agent..
我剛剛跟經紀人談過…
and the premiere is next week and you're all invited!
下星期有首映會 你們通通被邀請了
-Will we take a limo? -Sure!
-我們要坐加長禮車嗎？ -當然
I love taking limos when nobody died.
我喜歡在非葬禮的時候 搭加長禮車
Well, I won't be able to come.
我沒辦法去
For those who haven't checked their calendars, today's my due date.
那些還沒查過日曆的人聽好了 今天是我的預產期
You should come. Maybe you'll have the baby in the limo.
你應該來的 或許你會在加長禮車上生孩子
That way for the first few moments of her life, she'll think we're really fancy.
那樣她的人生第一刻看到我們 會覺得我們都很棒
I want to thank you guys for how great you've been during this.
我要謝謝你們 一直很支持我
I couldn't have done it without you. I loved these last 9 months.
沒有你們我絕對辦不到 我很喜歡過去的九個月
I'm looking forward to the next part..
我很期待下一個階段…
I am really gonna miss being pregnant.
我會很懷念懷孕的感覺
That's right. Still no baby.
沒錯，我還是沒生
What's the matter? Is the puffy, sweaty pregnant lady..
怎麼了？ 汗臭味十足的臃腫孕婦…
disturbing your precious coffee time?
打擾了你們寶貴的咖啡時間？
Come on, people, make some room.
大家快讓開
Sweetie, maybe you'd be more comfortable here.
或許你坐在這裡 會比較舒服
You.
你
Like you haven't done enough.
你似乎做的還不夠多
I know you're miserable. I wish there was something I could do.
我知道你很難過 我真的希望能幫上忙
I wish I were a sea horse.
我希望我是海馬
Because with sea horses, it's the male. They carry the babies.
因為是公海馬 負責孵育小寶寶
And then also, I'd be far away in the sea.
而且，我可以逃到海裡
God.
天啊
I have never been so uncomfortable in my entire life.
我這輩子 從來沒有這麼難受過
I know. I remember toward the end..
我瞭解，我記得…
That's a great story. Tell it while you're getting me some iced tea.
那是個很棒的故事 幫我拿冰茶來再說
Oh, God, get out! Get out, get out, get out!
天啊，滾出來，滾出來，滾出來
Let's.
走吧
The One Where Rachel Is Late
本集播出：遲來的寶寶
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Hey, did you have the baby yet?
你的寶寶生了嗎？
Do you want me to sit on you? Because I'll do it.
你要我坐在你身上嗎？ 因為我真的會那麼做
-What are you doing here? -They sent me home from work.
-你在這裡做什麼？ -公司要我回家
They said, "Start your maternity leave now. Just rest."
他們說「開始休產假 回家去休息吧」
You know what? Screw them!
你知道嗎？去他們的
If they don't want me there, I'll hang out with you guys.
如果他們不要我待在那裡 我可以跟你們鬼混
Or you could do volunteer work.
或許你可以去做義工
-Hello? -Joey, it's Estelle.
-哈囉 -喬伊，我是雅詩黛
I was able to get you and one guest tickets to your premiere.
我幫你跟你的一個朋友 弄到首映會的門票
-You told me I could have six tickets. -I sold four on eBay.
-你說我可以拿六張票 -我把四張拿去網站拍賣了
You'll be sitting next to HotGuy 372.
你得坐在帥哥372旁邊
So that's it? I only get to bring one guest?
就那樣？ 我只能帶一個朋友去？
Yeah. What time you wanna pick me up?
對 你什麼時候來接我？
Hello?
喂？
You hear that? I only get one extra ticket to my premiere.
你們聽到了嗎？ 我只能帶一個朋友參加首映會
So somehow I have to pick between you three and Ross.
所以我得在你們三個 跟羅斯之間做挑選
-What about me? -You said you didn't want to go.
-我呢？ -你說過你不想去
I don't. But I would still like to be acknowledged.
沒錯 但我還是希望有被重視的感覺
-Because I'm pregnant, I'm invisible? -Definitely not invisible.
-我懷孕了就變成隱形人？ -你絕不是隱形人
Ross didn't care enough to be here, so he's out.
羅斯根本不在這裡 所以他出局了
-You snooze, you lose. -He's not snoozing. He's teaching.
-你打瞌睡你就輸了 -他沒有打瞌睡，他在教書
Well, then somebody's snoozing.
那麼一定有人在打瞌睡
And, Joey, not that this should affect you at all, but if you pick me..
喬伊，我不是要你聽我的 但如果你選了我…
I was planning on wearing a sequin dress cut down to here.
我計劃穿露到這裡的 緊身洋裝
-I haven't seen this dress. -Star in a movie.
-我還沒有看過這套洋裝 -我可以當電影明星
Pick whoever you want. Listen to your heart. What does it tell you?
你想挑誰都可以，聽你的心說話 它跟你說了什麼？
Phoebe. Phoebe. Phoebe.
菲比…
Well..
這個嘛…
I think I want to take Chandler.
我想我要挑錢德
Phoebe, Phoebe, Phoebe.
菲比…
-You want to take me? -Yeah, I wish I could take everybody.
-你要挑我？ -對，我希望能帶大家去
But Chandler's always supported my career.
但錢德一直都很支持我的事業
He's paid for acting classes, headshots and stuff.
他幫我付表演課 跟沙龍照等等的費用
This will be my way of paying you back.
這就是我回報你的方式
So you're never actually going to pay me back?
所以你打算不還我錢？
Just because he paid for your headshots, you're gonna take him?
只因為他幫你付沙龍照的錢 你就要選他？
I don't think you're comprehending just how slutty this dress is.
我想你不瞭解那件洋裝有多露
It's not just the stuff he paid for. It's everything, you know?
不光只因為他付了錢 他真的很支持我，你們知道嗎？
He read lines with me. He went with me on auditions when I was nervous.
他跟我對台詞 我很緊張時陪我去試鏡
Then he consoled me after I didn't get parts that I wanted.
當我沒拿到我要的角色時 他會安慰我
You always believed in me, man, even when I didn't.
你一直相信我 即使連我都不相信自己
I always knew you were gonna make it. I'm so proud of you.
我一直都知道你會成功 我非常以你為榮
Thanks, that means a lot to me.
謝謝，那對我來說很重要
Mon, maybe one of these guys wants to wear your dress.
摩妮卡，或許他們之中 有人想穿你的洋裝
-I'm gonna go shave. -Yeah, well, I'm gonna go spit.
-我得去刮鬍子 -對，我得去吐痰了
I have to pee.
我得去尿尿了
If I don't come out, it's because I've choked to death on the potpourri stink.
五分鐘後如果我沒出來 那是因為我被花香味薰死了
You hold her nose, I'll blow in her mouth and the kid'll just.. out of her.
等她出來時你捏住她的鼻子 我對她的嘴巴吹氣，寶寶就會掉出來
She's a week late. She's got to have it today.
她晚了一個星期 今天她一定會生
I don't know. I think it's still gonna be a while.
我不知道 我想應該還要一陣子
Care to make it interesting?
你想加點刺激嗎？
-I bet you she'll have it tomorrow. -You're on.
-我跟你賭她明天會生 -沒問題
-Okay, how much? -One hundred thousand dollars.
-好吧，賭多少？ -10萬
-How about 50 bucks? -I'll call Zurich and move some money.
-50塊如何？ -我會打電話到蘇黎世請他們匯錢來
All right, whose turn is it to help me get up?
好了，這次輪到誰來扶我？
No one's here.
沒有人在
Oh, damn it!
該死
《在那邊》 （世界首映會）
This is exciting. So glamorous! People taking our picture. How do I look?
這真的是太刺激了，太棒了 好多人幫我們拍照，我看起來如何？
-A little tall. -What?
-太高了一點 -什麼？
Would you crouch down a bit so that I look taller?
你能不能蹲低一點 讓我看起來高一點？
There you go.
這樣好
It's just so glamorous.
真的是太棒了
Oh, hey, Mon? Rach is here.
摩妮卡，瑞秋來了
And you're still pregnant.
你還沒生
I'm sorry. I know how uncomfortable you are.
真對不起 我知道你很不舒服
You know what? You look great. Yeah, like 50 bucks.
你知道嗎？你看起來棒極了 就跟50塊鈔票一樣
I have to go pee. Apparently this baby thinks my bladder is a squeeze toy.
我得去尿尿，很明顯地這個寶寶 把我的膀胱當成玩具捏
Damn it. Here's your 50 bucks.
該死，50塊拿去
That's interesting that you lost. Now, I forget, do you like to lose?
你會輸真的是太有趣了 我忘了，你喜歡輸嗎？
All right, stop it.
好吧，別說了
-Double or nothing she has it tomorrow. -Fine.
-我們加倍來賭她明天會生 -好吧
Until then, General Grant, why don't you set up camp.. right there?
在那之前，葛蘭特將軍 你為什麼不在這裡…紮營？
-Rachel here? We have an appointment. -In the bathroom.
-瑞秋在這裡嗎？我們得去看醫生 -在廁所裡
-Rach, we gotta go. -In a minute!
-瑞秋，我們得走了 -馬上好
People ask why we're not together. I just don't know what to tell them.
大家問我們為什麼不在一起 我不知道該怎麼告訴他們
All right, let's go.
好吧，我們該走了
Oh, wait a minute.
等一下
Do I have to pee again?
我又得尿尿嗎？
No, I'm good.
不，我沒事
Do you want to go change first?
你要不要先去換衣服？
The doctor's staying open late for us, but if you hurry..
醫生會等我們 但如果你快一點…
-No, I'm fine. -You don't think that's inappropriate?
-不，我很好 -你不覺那套衣服很不適當嗎？
-What? -Good God, man. Don't anger it.
-什麼？ -天啊，別火上加油
Ross, it is 100 degrees outside. For the first time in weeks, I am..
羅斯，外面有一百度 這是好幾個星期以來我第一次…
Fine. Whatever you want. You're the mommy.
好吧，隨便你 你是媽咪
No! Don't call me "Mommy."
不，別叫我「媽咪」
It's bad enough you call your own mother that.
你那樣叫你媽就已經夠糟了
I'm actually with her on this one.
這一次我同意她的說法
Come on, Ross. We're gonna be late.
快點，羅斯 我們要遲到了
Either of you want to be Ross?
你們想不想當羅斯？
I thought I knew who the enemy was, but it was you.
我以為我知道敵人是誰 但敵人卻是你
Okay, this is it. This is my big fight scene coming up.
好吧 我的打鬥戲要開始了
I'm fighting for every man in the 82nd Ground Division.
我要打倒 82地面師的每個人
Ross? Can I ask you something?
羅斯 我能問你一件事嗎？
When Carol was pregnant with Ben..
卡蘿懷班的時候…
were you this irritating?
你有這麼暴躁嗎？
-Excuse me? -Nothing. You're just..
-你說什麼？ -沒事，你只是…
You've been a little short with me lately. I'm not trying to irritate you.
你最近對我很不耐煩 我不想惹毛你
Well, then, you must have a natural talent for it.
那麼你一定是有惹毛我的天份
The doctor will be in soon. Why don't we not speak until then?
醫生馬上到 在那之前我們還是別說話
Okay.
好吧
Seriously. Breathe louder, Ross. That's great.
說真的，呼吸大聲一點，羅斯 那真的太棒了
We should ask the doctor if she even knows..
我們應該問醫生 她知不知道…
how to deliver a baby that's half human, half pure evil!
怎麼接生半人半惡魔的孩子
-Hi, Dr. Long. How are you? -You're nice to her.
-朗醫生，你好嗎？ -你對她很好
She has the drugs.
她有藥
We'll do a quick check.
-我很快幫你檢查一下 -好的
Eight days late, huh? You must be getting uncomfortable.
已經遲了八天嗎？ 你一定會很不舒服
Yeah, just a tad.
對，只有一點
You're 80% effaced. You're on your way. It still could last a while.
寶寶已經下降了八成，就快了 但你可能還得等上一陣子
-There are ways to help things along. -Do them!
-如果你很急，有些方式可以幫助你 -那就做吧
Actually, they're things that you can do. Home remedies.
事實上你可以用這些方法 在家做治療
In my experience, I've found some are very effective.
根據我的經驗 我發現有些方法很有效
-Well, we are ready to try anything. -There's an herbal tea you can drink.
-我們願意嘗試任何事 -你可以喝一種藥草茶
You can take some castor oil. There's spicy foods.
你可以喝麻子油 吃辣的食物
We will do all of those.
我們全部都願意
-Taking a long walk. -Good. Done.
-散很久的步 -很好，沒問題
And there's the one that's proved most effective: sex.
根據證實最有效的方法 就是做愛
You've got to be kidding me!
你一定是在開玩笑
Good job, Joe! Well done! Top-notch!
演的好，喬伊，太棒了，一流的
-You liked it? You really liked it? -Oh, yeah!
-你真的喜歡嗎？ -喜歡
-Well, which part exactly? -The whole thing! Here we go!
-你喜歡哪個部份？ -全部，我們走吧
No, no, no. Give me some specifics.
不，說詳細一點
I loved the specifics. The specifics were the best part.
我喜歡全部 全部都很棒
Hey, what about the scene with the kangaroo? Did you like that part?
袋鼠的那一段呢？ 你喜歡嗎？
I was surprised to see a kangaroo in a World War I epic.
看到一次大戰的電影裡 出現袋鼠我嚇了一大跳
You fell asleep!
你睡著了
There was no kangaroo! They didn't take any of my suggestions!
片中沒有袋鼠 他們沒有接納我的意見
-I can't believe you fell asleep. -I can't believe it either.
-我不敢相信你睡著了 -我也不敢相信
Maybe it didn't happen.
或許它沒有發生
Maybe you fell asleep and dreamt the whole thing.
或許你睡著了 這一切都是你在做夢
And this conversation we're having right now is part of that dream.
我們現在的談話也是在你夢中
Wake up, Joe!
醒一醒，喬伊
-Thanks for coming. See you later. -Don't go. I'm so sorry.
-謝謝你來看，回頭見 -別走了，我很抱歉
Look, this guy fell asleep! He fell asleep too! Be mad at him!
聽著，這傢伙睡著了 他也睡著了，生他的氣啊
Or call an ambulance!
或是叫救護車來
What did the doctor say? Any news on when the baby will come?
醫生說什麼？ 知道寶寶何時會出生嗎？
No. She gave us ideas on how to induce labor.
不，她教我們 如何加速生產的腳步
We tried them all.
我們都試過了
We went for a walk, we tried tea, castor oil, spicy food. Nothing worked.
我們去散步，喝了茶 吃麻子油跟辣的食物，通通沒用
There is one thing we didn't try.
有個方法我們沒試
But someone thinks that that will open up a can of worms.
但有人覺得 那會惹來大麻煩
If it's gonna help bring the baby here, today..
什麼辦法？ 如果有辦法讓寶寶在今天出生…
I think you should do it.
我想你們應該試試看
-It's sex. -Do it!
-我們得做愛 -就做啊
-Monica. -It's been a really long time for you.
-摩妮卡 -你們很久沒做愛了
I mean, women have needs. Do it. Get yours.
我是說女人也有需要 快去吧，滿足你的需要
Oh, I don't know about that.
這個嘛，我不知道…
I think if the two of you had sex, the repercussions would be catastrophic.
我想如果你們兩個做愛 結果一定會很糟糕
All right, let's be practical.
好吧，我們實際一點
If Ross isn't willing, he's not the only guy you can have sex with.
如果羅斯不願意 不只他能跟你做愛
You could borrow Chandler. Chandler is good.
你可以借用錢德 錢德很厲害
Okay, okay. Yeah, I don't think I wanna do that.
好吧 我不想那麼做
You sure? I'm just saying..
你確定？我是說…
the baby's head isn't getting any smaller.
寶寶的頭不會愈變愈小
Monica, what is the matter with you?
摩妮卡，你是怎麼了？
-I just want the baby to be born today. -Why today?
-我只是希望寶寶能在今天出生 -為什麼一定要今天？
Okay, fine.
好吧
I bet Phoebe that you're gonna have the baby, and I don't want to lose.
我一直在跟菲比打賭你會生 我不想再輸錢了
What? While she's been going through this hell, you've been making money?
什麼？她這麼痛苦 你們卻在賭錢？
You're betting on your friend staying in this misery?
你們拿朋友是否會持續 這種難忍的痛苦來當賭注？
-I'll take that bet. -What?
-我要賭 -什麼？
I'm miserable. I may as well make some money out of it.
我已經夠慘了 還不如找點錢賺
Can I get some of that action?
我也可以加入嗎？
I'm betting against all of you?
等等，現在變成我跟你們三個對賭？
I really feel like tomorrow it's gonna happen.
別擔心 我真的覺得應該是明天
Okay.
好吧
Sixty,80,100.
60，80，100
And 50.
50塊
And two.
兩塊
Yeah, baby.
好耶，寶貝
Hey, Sleeping Beauty.
嘿，睡美人
Where have you been? I want to talk to you. I still feel bad.
你跑到哪裡去了？ 我想跟你談一談，我還是很難過
Oh, no. Were you upset? Did you lose sleep?
不，你很難過？ 你睡不著嗎？
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
The reason I came over is to settle things between us. You've done a lot for me.
我來這裡解決我們之間的問題 你幫了我很多忙
I wanted to pay you back with the premiere, but you missed it.
我請你去看首映會報答你 但你睡著了
-So how much do I owe you? -What?
-我欠你多少錢？ -什麼？
-I don't want to owe you anything. -You don't owe me.
-我不想欠你 -你不欠我
-I don't want your.. -We're doing this!
-我不要你的… -我們得這麼做
You got me my first headshots. How much?
你幫我付第一次沙龍照的費用 多少錢？
-I don't know, $500. -Okay, $500. What else?
-我不知道，五百塊 -好吧，五百塊，還有呢？
Then there was the second set. The infamous "booger" headshots.
還有第二組沙龍照 可怕的「怪物」大頭照
Okay, so that's another $500. That's 500 and 500. That's..
好吧，再加五百塊 五百加五百是…
-You want a calculator? -Please.
-你需要計算器嗎？ -謝謝
Here.
拿去
All right, what else?
好吧，還有呢？
Well, there's acting classes, stage-combat classes, tap classes..
還有表演課 舞台打鬥課，踢踏舞課…
Which we're still keeping under our hats.
還不只是那些
That dialect coach who helped you with a Southern accent.
我付錢請教練教你說南方腔
Which, after 20 hours of lessons, still came out Jamaican.
上了20小時的課後 你還是滿口牙買加腔
What the hell are you talking about? The South will rise again, man.
你在胡說什麼？ 「南方將會再起」
Yes, money well-spent.
對，那筆錢花得很值得
Okay, what else? Rent.
好吧，還有呢？房租
Two, three years of rent, utilities, food..
兩、三年的房租 雜支費、伙食費…
Okay, so I'm writing you a check for..
好吧 我寫張支票給你…
So you fell asleep during my movie. Big deal, right?
你看我的電影看到睡著了 沒什麼大不了的，對吧？
How do you clear this thing?
這玩意要怎麼消除？
Finish your enchilada.
把你的墨西哥卷吃掉
Ross, we've tried all the spicy food. It's not working.
羅斯，我們試過所有的辣食物 根本沒用
Okay, here, have one of these peppers.
好吧，拿去，吃根辣椒
Oh, God. So hot. Oh, my God.
天啊，好辣，我的天啊
By the way, you don't want to touch the pepper and then touch your eye.
還有拿過辣椒後別用手摸眼睛
I am feeling nothing.
我沒有感覺
Speaking of hot, watching you do that..
說到辣 看到你那麼做…
really makes me want to have sex with you.
真的讓我想跟你做愛
-Stop it. -Come on! Why are we wasting time?
-別鬧了 -快點，我們為什麼要浪費時間？
We know it's gonna work. It's doctor-recommended.
我們知道它會成功 這是醫生的建議
I'm sorry. But we have to have some boundaries. My God, I'm dying.
抱歉，但我們得謹守份際 天啊，我快辣死了
We've done it before. We'll do it again.
我們以前做過 可以再做一次
It'll be a nice way to bookend the pregnancy.
那是結束懷孕的好辦法
I'm not gonna make love to you so you'll go into labor.
我不會因為要讓你生孩子 就跟你做愛
Make love? What are you, a girl?
做愛？你是娘娘腔嗎？
Always a great way to get into a man's pants.
那是惹毛男人最棒的方法
You'll be performing a service. Think of me as a ketchup bottle.
你只是在提供服務 把我當成一罐蕃茄醬
Sometimes, you have to bang on the end of it to get it to come out.
有時候你得敲敲瓶底 才能把蕃茄醬倒出來
I love when you talk dirty to me.
我喜歡你說髒話的樣子
I know it. You're right. That's not sexy.
我知道，那說的對 那一點都不性感
Oh, I seem to have dropped my fork.
我的叉子掉了
Let me just bend over and get it.
我得彎下腰來撿它
Oh, God!
天啊
Okay, enough. This is not going to happen.
好吧，夠了 這是不可能發生的
Come on, Ross. I'm miserable here.
來吧，羅斯，我真的很難受
Come on, you started this, now you finish it!
來吧，這是你惹出來的 你得結束它
Come on, wuss. Make love to me.
來吧，懦夫，跟我做愛
-You know what? -What?
-你知道嗎？ -什麼？
Forget it.
算了
What now, Ross, you're not gonna talk?
怎麼了？羅斯 你不想談嗎？
How on earth will you ever annoy me?
你到底要惹我惹到什麼時候？
Oh, wait a minute, I know.
等一下，我知道了
You'd think the jalapeno would clear up your sinuses, but no!
你覺得辣椒能治好 你的鼻竇炎，但是你錯了
That's not enough.. What are you doing?
那還是不夠… 你在做什麼？
I'm getting that baby out of you!
我要讓你把寶寶生出來
-Oh, God! -I know.
-天啊 -我知道
Oh, no, no, no.
不
I think my water just broke.
我想我的羊水破了
I am good!
我太厲害了
Okay, I got the pillow. I got the bag.
好吧，我拿了枕頭 還有包包
-You got the keys? -I got the keys.
-你拿了鑰匙嗎？ -我拿了
We're having a baby.
我們的寶寶要出生了
I didn't have time to read this part of the books, but do we have time..?
我還來不及看書上這個部份 但我們有時間…
-Not so much. -Okay, let's go.
-我們的時間不多 -好吧，我們走吧
-200. -Thank you.
-兩百 -謝謝
That's it. I don't care when the baby comes. No more betting.
夠了，我不在乎寶寶何時出生 我不要賭了
Okay.
好吧
Hello?
喂？
I guess we could bet one more time.
我們再賭一次也無妨
-Is Rachel having the baby? -How did you know that?
-瑞秋要生了嗎？ -你怎麼知道？
-Joey! Chandler! -They're at the coffee house.
-喬伊，錢德，時間到了！ -他們在咖啡廳
You know everything!
你什麼都知道
Wait. I bet you the baby is over 7 pounds.
等一下 我跟你賭寶寶超過七磅重
I bet you it has hair! I bet you it's a girl.
我跟你賭寶寶有頭髮 我跟你賭是女兒
-We know it's a girl. -I'll give you really good odds.
-我們知道她要生女兒 -我給你很高的賠率